Register of the Harry S. Kantor Papers, 1948-1977.
Hoover Institution Archives
Harry S. Kantor Papers,
1948-1977
81049
Kantor, Harry S., 1903-
32 manuscript boxes (13.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, notes, legislation, and printed matter, relating to the American labor force, wages and hours regulation, unemployment and retirement benefits, encouragement of inventors in the United States, and the enactment of a minimum wage law in the Philippines.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Dept. of Labor.; Labor laws and legislation--Philippines.; Labor laws and legislation--United States.; Philippines.; United States--Politics and government.; Inventors--United States.
Biographical Note
1903, November 3 Born, Russia
1924 B.A., Columbia University
1925 M.A., Columbia University
1926-1938 Staff, Department of Agriculture and other government agencies
1938-1955 Price analyst, economist, statistician, Department of Labor
1954 Member, U.S. delegation to negotiate current trade agreement with the Philippine Islands
1955-1958 Assistant administrator, Department of Labor, Wage and Hour and Public Contracts Division
1958-1969 Analyst, Department of Labor, Office of Research and Development
1963-1977 Member, Department of Commerce, National Inventors Council
Series Description
- Correspondence, 1950-1975. (Box No. 1.)
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
- National Inventors Council, 1963-1977. (Box No. 1-7.)
  Reports, correspondence, memoranda, lists, writings, clippings, and printed matter arranged alphabetically by subject.
- U.S. Department of Labor. Office of Research and Development. 1948-1973. (Box No. 7-22.)
  Reports, printed matter, correspondence, Department of Labor studies, writings, graphs, statistical data, clippings, and other material, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Subject File, 1950-1976. (Box No. 22-32.)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, newsletters, lists, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Writings, 1958-1969. (Box No. 32.)
  Writings of H. S. Kantor arranged alphabetically by title. Untitled writings arranged alphabetically by subject.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1950-1975
  - Bardeen, John, 1975 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Brundage, Kenneth P., 1960 (Folder 2)
  - Davis, Joseph S., 1960 (Folder 3)
  - Dicorcia, E. T., 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Fisher, Paul, 1960 (Folder 5)
  - Gomperts, Henry G., 1950 (Folder 6)
  - Gude, Gilbert, 1970 (Folder 7)
  - Hewitt, William B., 1971 (Folder 8)
  - Hollomon, J. Herbert, 1965 (Folder 9)
  - Koch, H. William, 1975 (Folder 10)
  - Kuznets, Simon, 1971 (Folder 11)
  - La Rocca, Joseph J., 1971 (Folder 12)
  - Morabe, Emiliano, 1951 (Folder 13)
  - Neumeyer, Fredrik, 1965 (Folder 14)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1973 (Folder 15)
  - Peterson, John M., 1960 (Folder 16)
  - Pope, Alexander H., 1960 (Folder 17)
  - Porath, Rabbi Tzvi H., 1975 (Folder 18)
  - Prescott College, 1970 (Folder 19)
  - Proxmire, William, 1969 (Folder 20)
  - Rabinow, Jacob, 1975 (Folder 21)
  - Reder, Melvin W., 1960 (Folder 22)
  - Roxas, Antonio V., 1952 (Folder 23)
  - Schubert, Richard F., 1970 (Folder 24)
  - Stedman, John C., 1970 (Folder 25)
  - Tiep, Brian L., 1970 (Folder 26)
  - Van Valkenburg, Alvin, 1971 (Folder 27)
  - Who's Who, 1971 (Folder 28)
  - Wyckoff, Florence R., 1960 (Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 30)
- NATIONAL INVENTORS COUNCIL, 1963-1977
  - Anagnostopoulos, Costas E., "Management of Risk in Innovation," speech at Commercial Chemical Development Association, New York, March 16, 1965 (Box 1., Folder 31)
  - Biebel, Lawrence, "The National Inventors Council and Creativity," December 1969 (Folder 32)
  - Bollay, William
    - General (Folder 33-34)
    - "Case Studies - As a Stimulant to Technical Innovation," n.d. (Folder 35)
    - "How Can We Increase the Inventor's Contribution to Society?", n.d. (Folder 36)
    - "Increasing the Contribution of Inventors," October 1968 (Folder 37)
    - "System Engineering for the Future," n.d. (Folder 38)
  - Bollay Committee on Engineering Education, 1971 (Folder 39)
  - Bright, James R., "Technological Forecasting for Industry and Government; Methods and Applications" (Folder 40)
  - Brochure topic and conference, January 1971 (Folder 41)
  - Centers of Technological Innovation, proposal for, 1970 (Folder 42)
  - Charter (Folder 43)
  - Coler, Myron, "The Nature of the Inventor," September 1968 (Folder 44)
  - "A Commerce Department Program to Support the Education of Prospective Inventors, Innovators and Entrepreneurs," November 1969 (Folder 45)
  - Commerce Technical Advisory Board (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Committee No. 3
    - General (Folder 2)
    - The employed inventor (Folder 3)
  - Committee No. 5, Creativity in engineering education (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence
    - Anagnostopoulos, Costas E., 1965-1971 (Folder 5-6)
    - Arnow, Philip, 1968 (Folder 7)
    - Bollay, William, 1966-1971 (Folder 8)
    - De Simone, Daniel V., 1966-1871 (Folder 9)
    - Draper, C. Stark, 1969-1973 (Folder 10)
    - Hodges, Luther H., 1964 (Folder 11)
    - Ide, John M., 1969 (Folder 12)
    - Oliver, Philip M., 1969 (Folder 13)
    - Rabinow, Jacob, 1974 (Folder 14)
    - Reynolds, James, 1963 (Folder 15)
    - Rines, Robert H., 1975 (Folder 16)
    - Rosow, Jerome M., 1969-1970 (Folder 17)
    - Rossman, Joseph, 1968 (Folder 18)
    - Schon, Donald A., 1963 (Folder 19)
    - Stedman, John C., 1970-1971 (Folder 20)
    - Walker, Brooks, 1970 (Box 3., Folder 1)
    - Wirtz, W. Willard, 1965-1967 (Folder 2)
  - Davis, Watson, "Proposal for a Grant to Promote Technologic Inventiveness Among Teen-Age Youth," 1965 (Folder 3)
  - De Simone, Daniel V., "The Patent System in a Changed and Changing Environment," address at Annual Convention of the Federal Bar Association, Washington, D.C., September 1964 (Folder 4)
  - Draper, Charles Stark
    - General (Folder 5)
    - "Mathematical Approximations for the Technology of Navigation, Control and Guidance of Space Vehicles," 1970 (Folder 6)
    - "Military Technology and the Future of Mankind," September 1970 (Folder 7)
    - Paper at the National Conference on Creative Engineering Education, Woods Hole, Massachusetts, September, 1965 (Folder 8)
    - "A Position Paper on the Special Laboratories," February 1970 (Folder 9)
    - "Systems Engineering and Modern Technology," reprint, Engineering Education, Vol. 60, No. 8, April 1970 (Folder 10)
    - "Technology, Creativity and the Changing Social Environment," October 1970 (Folder 11)
    - "Technology, Engineering, Science and Modern Education," June 1967 (Folder 12)
  - Engineering education (Folder 13)
  - Engineering projects (Folder 14)
  - European Institute of Science and Technology, Study Committee on the Creation of a, May 1968 (Folder 15)
  - Ezra, Arthur, "Proposed Center for Innovation and Technology as a Stimulus to Design Engineering," December 1969 (Folder 16)
  - Function (Folder 17)
  - Government observers, July 1970 (Folder 18)
  - Hardland, Leonard S., "Experimental Invention Program," a proposal, n.d. (Folder 19)
  - International Labor Organization (Folder 20)
  - "The Inventor and His Government," July 1967 (Folder 21)
  - "The Inventor and Society," November 20, 1968 (Folder 22)
  - Jaramillo, Edward J., "Public Sector Problems Suitable for Systems Engineering Research," 1968 (Folder 23)
  - Kantor, Harry S.
    - Membership (Folder 24)
    - Writings
      - "The Inventor, Technological Creativity, and Society," April 1968. Typescript (photocopy) (Folder 25)
      - Notes (Folder 26-27)
      - "Notes Relating to the New Committee of NIC," April 1965. Typescript (photocopy) (Folder 28)
      - Proposal for a conference "The Inventor and Social Problems," 1967. Typescript (Folder 29)
  - Long Range Planning Committee (Box 4., Folder 1)
  - Long Range Planning Sub-Panel, 1977 (Folder 2)
  - Meetings
    - May 9, 1964 (Folder 3)
    - September 17-19, 1964 (Folder 4)
    - February 1, 1965 (Folder 5)
    - May 19-21, 1965 (Folder 6)
    - January 21, 1966 (Folder 7)
    - March 25, 1966 (Folder 8)
    - January 18, 1967 (Folder 9)
    - March 2-3, 1967 (Folder 10)
    - May 8, 1967 (Folder 11)
    - October 26, 1967 (Folder 12)
    - January 8-9, 1968 (Folder 13)
    - March 14, 1968 (Folder 14)
    - May 14, 1968 (Folder 15)
    - October 9-11, 1968 (Folder 16)
    - Woods Hole, 1968 (Folder 17)
    - May 22-23, 1969 (Folder 18)
    - November 17, 1969 (Folder 19)
    - January 12, 1970 (Folder 20)
    - June 17, 1970 (Folder 21)
    - December 11-12, 1970 (Folder 22)
    - October 12, 1971 (Folder 23)
    - December 14, 1971 (Folder 24)
    - November 9, 1973 (Folder 25)
    - June 18, 1974 (Box 5., Folder 1)
  - Members (Folder 2)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1963-1964 (Folder 3)
  - National Academy of Enginering. Commission on Education. "A Proposed Policy for Mineral Resource Development in Engineering Schools for the Department of the Interior," report of a panel, March 25/26, 1971 (Folder 4)
  - National Conference on Creative Engineering Council, Woods Hole, Massachusetts, September 1-4, 1965 (Folder 5)
  - Navy/Marine Corps Research and Development Problems, 1967 (Folder 6)
  - Neumeyer, Fredrik
    - General (Folder 7)
    - "The Employed Inventor - The European Situation - The American Situation," n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Ownership and amount of compensation for inventions and proposals for technical improvement made by employed persons (Folder 9)
  - Papers distributed (Folder 10)
  - Patent Advisory Committee (Folder 11)
  - Patents (Folder 12-14)
  - Patents (Box 6., Folder 1)
  - Perry, R. J., "Survey of Engineering Creativity," 1969 (Folder 2)
  - Planning Committee (Folder 3-4)
  - Preliminary Report of the NIC on Senate Bill S. 1042 and Corresponding H.R. 5924, April 1967 (Folder 5)
  - President's Commission on the Patent System, report to, May 1966 (Folder 6)
  - Recommendations, March 1965 (Folder 7)
  - Resolutions, October 13, 1970 (Folder 8)
  - Ruben, Samuel, "How Society Helps or Hinders the Activities of the Inventor," August 1968 (Folder 9)
  - Science Talent Search (Folder 10)
  - Senate Bill S. 1042 and corresponding H.R. 5924 (Folder 11)
  - Stedman, John
    - Report of the Subcommittee on Intellectual Property re Proposed Brochure and Conference, November 23, 1970 (Folder 12)
    - "Rights and Responsibilities of the Employed Inventor," February 23, 1968 (Folder 13)
    - "Role of the Inventor in Society," brochure and conference, October 1970 (Folder 14)
    - "The Value of the Inventor to Society," September 1968 (Folder 15)
  - Subcommittee on Intellectual Property, report, May 1970 (Folder 16)
  - "The Technological Inventor and Society," symposium planned, September 1968 (Folder 17)
  - URBA IV - An Experimental Urban Transport Vehicle, April 1968 (Folder 18)
  - U.S. Department of Commerce. Office of State Technical Services. 1969-1970 (Folder 19)
  - U.S. Department of Labor. Office of the Assistant Secretary for Administration
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1971 (Folder 20)
    - Memoranda, 1970 (Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 22-23)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7., Folder 1-2)
- U.S. DEPARTMENT OF LABOR. OFFICE OF RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT. 1948-1973
  - Abernathy, Rev. R. D., and the Poor Peoples Campaign, June 1968 (Box 7., Folder 3)
  - Activity Analysis of Production of Knowledge by the Department of Labor - Manpower (excluding automation), August 30, 1963 (Folder 4)
  - Agency Program Planning Officers group luncheon, November 6, 1962 (Folder 5)
  - Agricultural workers
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Minimum wage, 1959-1962 (Folder 7)
    - Voluntary Farm Employment Service Act, June 12, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Agriculture census, 1964 (Folder 9)
  - Alterman, Jack, "The Sources of Economic Growth in the United States - A Critique," July 17, 1964 (Folder 10)
  - "America's Job-Creating Capacity Versus Its Increase in People Needing Jobs," n.d. (Folder 11)
  - American foreign labor policy, 1961 (Folder 12)
  - Anti-Poverty Bill, 1964 (Folder 13)
  - Apprenticeship, Departmental policies and plans (Folder 14)
  - Bernal, John Desmond, "World Without War," n.d. (Folder 15)
  - Bills in the U.S. Congress (Folder 16-17)
  - Budget (Box 8., Folder 1-2)
  - Bureau of the Budget, 1965 Review (Folder 3)
  - Child labor (Folder 4-5)
  - Clague, Ewan, "Family Income in Relation to Family Size and Needs," memorandum, December 17, 1964 (Folder 6)
  - Clark, John M., "The Wage-Price Problem," summary and comments on, June 1, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Commission on the Patent System, 1959-1964 (Folder 8)
  - Consumer interests, 1962-1963 (Folder 9)
  - Continuing education (Folder 10)
  - Correspondence
    - Arnow, Philip, 1965-1966 (Folder 11)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1963-1965 (Folder 12-13)
    - Shockley, William B., 1965 (Folder 14)
    - Wirtz, W. Willard, 1965 (Folder 15)
  - "A Cost-Benefit Analysis of the Enforcement Activities Under the Fair Labor Standards Act," November 1967 (Folder 16)
  - Cox, Archibald, "Student Attitudes and Concerns," Columbia Forum, 1968 (Folder 17)
  - Davis Bacon Act (Box 9., Folder 1)
  - Delahanty, George E. and Evans, Robert, Jr., "Low Wage Employment: An Inventory and an Assessment," n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Department Management Committee, 1967-1968 (Folder 3-5)
  - Department of Labor Management System, 1966-1968 (Folder 6)
  - Departmental automation and Manpower research, January 15, 1965 (Folder 7)
  - Departmental Histories Project, 1968 (Folder 8)
  - "A Design for Rural America," n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Developing countries in which the Department of Labor advises and assists labor unions (Folder 10)
  - Disability insurance, temporary (Folder 11)
  - Douty, H. M.
    - "Survey Methods and Wage Comparisons," reprint, Labor Law Journal, April 1964 (Folder 12)
    - "Wage Differentials: Forces and Counterforces," reprint, Monthly Labor Review, March 1968 (Folder 13)
  - Economic growth (Folder 14)
  - Economic Growth and Employment Opportunities Project, 1962 (Folder 15)
  - EDA meeting, June 20, 1967 (Folder 16)
  - Effect of import quotas on consumer interests, August 1969 (Folder 17)
  - Employed inventor (Folder 18)
  - Employed Incentive Act, 1967 (Folder 19)
  - Employment Service placement goals, February 1964 (Folder 20)
  - Employment tests (Box 10., Folder 1)
  - Executive Office of the President. Bureau of the Budget. Report on Urban Research, May 1963 (Folder 2)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act (Folder 3-8)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act (Box 11., Folder 1-2)
  - Fall Civil Rights Conference Task Force, May-August 1965 (Folder 3)
  - Family budgets: rationale (Folder 4)
  - Federal Advisory Council, Subcommittee on Unemployment Insurance (Folder 5)
  - Federal assistance to state and local governments (Folder 6)
  - Federal Manpower Programs (Folder 7)
  - "Federalism in Labor Legislation," n.d. (Folder 8)
  - "Five Year Plan: Policy Problems: Gaps in the 1963 Projections, and Subjects Needing Further Development," October 31, 1963 (Folder 9)
  - Five year projections (Folder 10-13)
  - Five year projections (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Foreign assistance (Folder 3)
  - Goal statements, October 1965 (Folder 4)
  - Goldberg, Arthur J.
    - "Occupational Training and Retraining under the Redevelopment Act," August 1961 (Folder 5)
    - "Working Hours in Excess of 40 Per Week," May 1962 (Folder 6)
  - Goodman, Elliot, "The Soviet Design for a World State," 1960 (Folder 7)
  - Graduate student deferments, proposal to extend, June 5, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Growth Studies Program (Folder 9)
  - Harvard Student Research Inquiry, December 1961 (Folder 10)
  - Higher education (Folder 11)
  - Highway costs, 1960 (Folder 12)
  - International labor
    - General (Folder 13)
    - Fostering reasonable expectations in developing countries compatible with U.S. security and ideals, March 25, 1964 (Folder 14)
    - Shaping aid programs in terms of the setting in the host country (Folder 15)
  - Job Developing Program (Folder 16)
  - Kantor, Harry S., writings
    - "BES Proposal for Legislation on VI." 1963. Holograph (Folder 17)
    - "Bonding As a Barrier to Placement at Youth Projects," memorandum for D. P. Moynihan, June 16, 1964. Typescript (Folder 18)
    - "General Purpose Economic and Labor Statistics," January 25, 1965. Typescript (Box 13., Folder 1)
    - "ILO Convention and Recommendation No. 122 Concerning Employment Policy," August 12, 1965. Typescript (photocopy) (Folder 2)
    - Notes, general (Folder 3)
    - Notes for 1965 Review (Folder 4)
    - "Notes for Meeting with Women's Bureau," memorandum to Philip Arnow, January 9, 1964. Typescript (carbon copy) (Folder 5)
    - "Planning and Analysis for FY 1969-1973 Program," 1966. Typescript (photocopy) (Folder 6)
    - "Planning Assumptions," 1964. Typescript (photocopy) (Folder 7)
    - PPBS, purpose of, August 22, 1968. Handwritten draft (Folder 8)
  - Kantor, Harry S., writings
    - "Questions for Consideration in Preparation for the 1964 Review of Five Year Projections," September 1963. Typescript (photocopy) (Folder 9)
    - Report to the Secretary of Labor, "The Railroad Unemployment Insurance System: Proposals and Policy Issues," July 20, 1962 (Folder 10)
    - "Special Studies," memorandum to King Carr, January 25, 1966. Typescript (carbon copy) (Folder 11)
    - "Task Force Paper on Agriculture and Rural Life," September 22, 1965. Typescript (photocopy) (Folder 12)
    - "Two Decades of the Fair Labor Standards Act," October 1958. Reprint, Monthly Labor Review (Folder 13)
    - Untitled drafts (Folder 14-15)
    - "Wage and Labor Standards" (Catagory IV)
      - "Federal Grants to State Labor Departments," July 1966. Typescript (Folder 16)
      - "Investigation Program," July 1966. Typescript (Folder 17)
      - "Occupational Safety: Federal Grants to States," July 1966. Typescript (Folder 18)
    - "WHPC: Central Questions," March 10, 1966. Typescript (Photocopy) (Folder 19)
    - "WHPC Planning Goal, 1967-1971," memorandum, March 12, 1965. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - Koenigsberg, E., "Models of Manpower Utilization and Manpower Needs," June 1966 (Folder 21)
  - Labor force and defense buildup, July-August 1965 (Folder 22)
  - Labor-management relations (Folder 23)
  - Labor-management services, 1963 (Box 14., Folder 1)
  - Labor-Management Services Administration planning goals for fiscal years, 1967-1971 (Folder 2)
  - Labor standards (Folder 3)
  - Latin America, problems of tax administration in, 1965 (Folder 4)
  - Legislative Program, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Low income aged, proposal for aiding, May 7, 1965 (Folder 6)
  - "Macesich and Stewart on Minimum Wage Effect Studies: A Comment," June 16, 1960 (Folder 7)
  - "Manpower Accounting for Youth: A National Inventory of Young People in Trouble,": July 1964 (Folder 8-9)
  - Manpower Administration (Folder 10)
  - "Manpower and Economic Policy," 1969 (Folder 11)
  - Manpower development and training goals (Folder 12)
  - Manpower Development Assistance, FY 1969-1973 (Folder 13)
  - Mentally retarded, employment of (Folder 14)
  - Mexican Program (Folder 15)
  - Migrant farm labor (Folder 16)
  - Migrant Manpower Corporation Act, 1967 (Folder 17)
  - Minimum wage (Folder 18)
  - Minimum wage (Box 15., Folder 1)
  - "The Motivation of Ghetto Residents toward Manpower Development Programs," 1968 (Folder 2)
  - Mundstuk, Jay, "Airlie House Retreat Agenda," April 23, 1968 (Folder 3)
  - NASA, 1963 (Folder 4)
  - National Inventors Council, symposium planned on "The Technological Inventor and Society," September 9, 1968 (Folder 5)
  - "The Negro Family - The Case for National Action," March 1965 (Folder 6)
  - "Note on Alternative Methods of Excluding Effect of Shifts on Output Per Man-Hour," May 19, 1960 (Folder 7)
  - Older worker and youth, 1965 (Folder 8)
  - On the job training and work-study arrangements (Folder 9)
  - Overtime
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Penalty rate for (Folder 11)
  - Planning, 1967-1971
    - LSB (Folder 12)
    - Notes on policy papers, 1964 (Folder 13)
    - WHPC (Folder 14)
  - "Planning and Analysis for FY 1969-1973 Program Memoranda," November 28, 1966 (Folder 15)
  - Planning cycle, FY 1969-1973 (Folder 16)
  - Planning goals, 1965-1971 (Box 16., Folder 1)
  - Planning Staff paper - "Problem and Solutions in the Coordination of Manpower Programs," n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Policy gaps, 1963 (Folder 3)
  - Porter, Richard C., "A Growth Model Forecast of Faculty Size and Salaries in United States Higher Education," reprint, Review of Economics and Statistics, Vol. 47, May 1965 (Folder 4)
  - Post Vietnam (Folder 5)
  - Poverty, programs against (Folder 6-7)
  - Poverty Bill - Department of Labor proposal's prepared at request of Secretary Wirtz, February 22, 1964 (Folder 8)
  - President Nixon's message to Congress, October 11, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - President's Commission on the Patent System, 1964 (Folder 10)
  - Private employment agencies (Box 17., Folder 1)
  - Productivity: goals and objectives, March 26, 1964 (Folder 2)
  - Program Budget Advisory Committee, 1965 Review, 1967-1971 (Folder 3)
  - Program Planning and Review Committee, meeting, April 6, 1961 (Folder 4)
  - Program plans (Folder 5)
  - Program statement on poverty (Folder 6)
  - Projects in progress (Folder 7)
  - Proposed award for inventors (Folder 8)
  - Provisional report, November 1962 (Folder 9)
  - Public Contracts Act (Folder 10)
  - Public Contracts wage determinations, effect on US foreign trade, 1962 (Folder 11)
  - Public employment (Folder 12-13)
  - Public Law 78 (Folder 14)
  - Railroad retirement and employment insurance (Folder 15-16)
  - Railroad unemployment insurance (Folder 17)
  - Railroad unemployment insurance (Box 18., Folder 1-2)
  - Reports, 1958-1962 (Folder 3)
  - Reports to the Secretary of Labor
    - The Railroad Unemployment Insurance System: Proposals and Policy Issues, July 10, 1962 (Folder 4)
    - Summary of a Study on Problems Involved in Applying a Minimum Wage to Agricultural Workers, March 7, 1960 (Folder 5)
  - Research program on problems of poverty (Folder 6)
  - Ryan, William, "The Negro Family (The Moynihan Report)," October 8, 1965 (Folder 7)
  - Safety programs (Folder 8)
  - Schwenger, Robert B., "Fair Labor Standards in International Trade," October 1966 (Folder 9)
  - Scientific and technical manpower and education (Folder 10)
  - Secretary of Labor's Planning Goals in the Field of Economics and Labor Statistics for Fiscal Years, 1967-1971 (Folder 11)
  - Secretary's staff meeting, November 4, 1964 (Folder 12)
  - Shorter work week (Folder 13)
  - Small business, November 1961 (Folder 14)
  - Snow, C. P., "Two Cultures and the Scientific Revolution," 1959 (Folder 15)
  - "Social Designs for American Enterprise," October 1965 (Folder 16)
  - "A Social Profile of the Spanish Speaking Migratory Farm Laborer," n.d. (Box 19., Folder 1)
  - Social Security (Folder 2)